

### Summary

Passionate software engineer with demonstrated expertise in web application development, API development, OOP best-practices, relational database systems, and agile project management. Background experience building applications using C#, Rails, and JavaScript (React.js, jQuery, AJAX). Grounded in the belief that all software design decisions should be rooted in solid UX principles with performance and security kept top of mind. Work well in fast-paced team and solo environments. First mobile application project managed saved lives and grossed \$5,000,000 within the first 30 days. Excited to learn new technologies.

# **Employment**

Quicken Loans

Software Develop

Detroit, MI Oct 2015 to Current

· Manage production-level enterprise applications

- Build APIs/web services in C# .NET with a focus on performance and security
- Conduct code reviews

TimeCard Contract Project Manager Rochester, MI Dec 2014 to Feb 2015

- Oversaw planning and development of flagship product web/mobile app
- Created company standards for project reports

DBA Worldwide

Project Manager

Rochester, MI May 2012 to Dec 2014

- Managed teams of 2-8 creative professionals in producing advertisements for digital and TV
- Managed the development of websites and mobile applications for: Henry Ford Health System, Coca-Cola, Northeastern University, and Trilogy Automotive

# **Projects**

#### DocServices (C#) - Role: Software Developer

DocServices is a decoupled web service with accompanying desktop app built to allows internal clients format loan documents. This project is currently in production at Quicken Loans.

- Added e-sign integration
- Service endpoints
- Conduct code reviews and suggest new features

Environment: C# .NET, API, MVC, SQL

### Xbert (C#) - Role: Software Developer

Xbert is an internal management dashboard that allows users to manage their web applications.

- Added admin portals for a more friendly non-technical end-user experience
- Conduct code reviews and suggest new features

Environment: C# .NET, SQL

### Polisee.io (Rails | React) - Role: Co-founder, Lead Engineer

Polisee empowers citizens by connecting them with issues they care about and the representatives who vote on those issues. Created to provide transparency and communication between the people and those who govern them. This was a group project.

- Developed almost all of the front-end using React.js, HTML/CSS, and Materialize
- Governed architectural design decisions for the project
- Integrated Twitter OAuth
- Built out backend structure, sessions and teams/about portions of the backend using scaffold and Rails
- Developed financial charts display on the front-end using Chartjs

Environment: RoR, Rspec, React.js, Heroku, PostgreSQL, HTML/CSS, Materialize, Twitter OAuth and Twilio API integration

### Pairly (In Progress) - Role: Full-Stack Developer

Pairly is a collaborative pair-programming platform for developers. Used by programmers for learning/teaching, partnering on projects, and interviewing. This is a solo project.

- Developed the backend in Ruby on Rails and PostgreSOL
- Developed the front-end in Rails and React.js using JSX

Environment: RoR, Rspec, React.js, Heroku, PostgreSQL, Github API, Google Closure API, FireBase API, and Ace-Editor API

# **Volunteering**

### Dev Bootcamp - Peer Mentor

Provided educational assistance and mentoring to new boots, helping acclimate them to the intense academic expectations and requirements at Dev Bootcamp. Developed and presented lectures on Computer Science and algorithm design.

### Django Girls Detroit Coach

 $\label{thm:continuous} Teach\ groups\ of\ women\ and\ men\ how\ to\ program\ using\ JavaScript,\ Github\ and\ the\ Django\ framework.$ 

# Education

Rasmussen College - GPA 3.04

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Computer Science 2017

Dev Bootcamp

Full-stack Web Development Software Engineering 2015

Oakland University

Certification Project Management 2013

## **Skills**

#### **RUBY**

Rails

Sinatra

Rspec

### **JAVASCRIPT**

React.js

jQuery AJAX

GreenSock

#### SQL

PostgreSQL

SQLite3

### WEB

HTML

CSS

### C#

.NET

MVC API

Moq

### **CONCEPTS**

SOLID

TDD Sna

APIs (REST)

Design Patterns

### TOOLS

Git Github

Eclipse

Xcode

Heroku

TFS

Visual Studio

Microsoft SQL Server

### OTHER

C

Java

Angularjs GreenSock

## **Contact**

**■** philborel21@gmail.com

philborel.me

**4** (248) 202-8541

**♀** Detroit, MI

in /in/philborel